Scripts should be considered as behaviour
スクリプトは Unity における Behaviour コンポーネントとして
components in Unity.
とらえるべきです。
As with other components in Unity they can
Unityの他のコンポーネントと同様に
be applied to objects and are seen
オブジェクトに適用して、
in the inspector.
インスペクタで表示できます。
With this particular example, this cube
この特定のサンプルで、キューブは
has a rigidbody component which gives it
Rigidbody コンポーネントがあり、
a physical mass. And when you press play
物理的な質量が与えられます。そしてゲーム再生したとき
the cube falls to the ground
重力を使用するため
as it uses gravity.
キューブは地面に落ちます。
We also have added an examples script.
あらかじめサンプルのスクリプトを追加してあります。
This behaviour script has code in it
この Behaviour スクリプトはコードが含まれていて
which changes the colour of the cube
キューブの色を変更します。
by effecting the colour value of the
これはオブジェクトにアタッチされたデフォルト マテリアルの
default material attached to that object.
color 変数を変更することで実現されます。
When we press the R key on the keyboard
キーボードの R  キーを押下すると
the colour gets changed to red.
色は赤に変更されます。
When we press G the colour gets
G キーを押下すると、
changed to green. And when we press B
カラーは緑色に変更されます。そして B キーを押下すると
it gets changed to blue.
青色に変更されます。
By attaching this script to the object
ゲームオブジェクトを参照する時にこのスクリプトを
when we refer to game object
オブジェクトにアタッチすることで、
we're referring to this particular item.
この特定のアイテムを指しています。
We then drill down to the value that we want
次に必要な値にドリルダウンして
and effect it. Here we're addressing the
変更します。ここでは
game object this script is attached to,
このスクリプトがアタッチされているゲームオブジェクトをみつけて、
we're then addressing the renderer,
次にレンダラをみつけます。
which is the component seen here,
すなわち、ここで表示されているコンポーネント
mesh renderer. We're then addressing the
Mesh Renderer です。次に
material attached to that renderer and
Renderer にアタッチされたマテリアルをみつけて、
finally the colour of that material.
最終的にマテリアルの色をみつけます。
And we're setting it to a shortcut called red
そして、Color クラスの一部である Red に
which is part of the colour class.
セットします。
Let's see this in action.
実際に実行してみます。
If I press play, then use the R, G or B
ゲーム再生して、キーボードの R, G, または B キーを使用すると
keys on the keyboard I can change the colour.
色を変更することが出来ます。
And you can see that the material
そしてマテリアルが変更されるのが
is being effected.
確認できます。
So this material is applied to the renderer,
Renderer には
default diffuse, you can see that listed there,
ここに表示された Default Diffuse マテリアルが適用されます。
and we're then effecting the main colour value
そして mainColor の値を変更して
and setting it to a certain value in here.
ここで特定の値をセットします。
The same as it would if I was actually
これは手動でエディタで変更した
doing it by hand in the editor.
場合と同様の結果です。
Scripts can be created in the project panel
スクリプトはプロジェクトパネルで作成するには
by choosing Create and then choosing
Create を選択して、それから
a language of your choice.
好みの言語を選択します。
For example,
例えば、
they can then be attached to objects either
オブジェクトにアタッチするには
by dragging and dropping
ドラッグ＆ドロップするか、
or by choosing the Add Component button
Component メニューの下にある
at the bottom of the Component menu
Add Component ボタンを使用して
and then choosing from the list of scripts
現在のプロジェクトのスクリプトの一覧から
in your current project.
選択を行います。
Scripts can also be created using the
スクリプトを作成するには
Add Component button by choosing
Add Component ボタンを使用して
New Script from the bottom and naming
下から New Script を選択して、
the script and selecting a language type
スクリプトの名前をつけたうえで言語タイプを
from the drop-down menu.
ドロップダウンメニューから選択します。
This can then be created and added in one step.
これは作成および追加をひとつのステップで出来ます。
The final way to add a script to your
オブジェクトにスクリプトを追加する最後の方法は
object is to select the object in the hierarchy
Hierarchy ビューでオブジェクトを選択して
and then choose Components - Scripts
Components - Scripts を選択し、
and then choose from the list of scripts
さらに現在のプロジェクトでのスクリプトの一覧から
in your current project. Of course you can
選択することです。
apply scripts to do all manner of other
スクリプトによりオブジェクトであらゆる動作を
behaviours of objects. Try to think of
実現できます。
scripts as components that you create
スクリプトは、自身で作成できるコンポーネントのようなものであり、
yourself, allowing you to create
Behaviour をゲームにおける
behaviour for different game objects in
異なるゲームオブジェクトとすることが出来ますし
your game, this could be characters,
文字列とすることが出来ます。
it could be environments or it could be
これは環境かもしれませんし、
scripts that manage the functionality
ゲームの機能を管理するスクリプト
of the game.
かもしれません。
This example script that we've looked at
みてきたこのサンプル スクリプトは C# で
is written in C# but in Unity
書かれてますが
you can write in Javascript, C# and Boo.
Unity では Javascript, C# および Boo で書けます。
Boo is a derivative of Python, though
Boo は Python からの派生ですが、
it's not as commonly used as the other two.
他の二つに比べるとあまり多く使用されていません。
So you'll likely see Javascript or C#
このためウェブで Unity のスクリプトを探すと
examples when you see scripting
Javascript または C# を
from Unity around the web. The videos
見かけることが多いはずです。
that you see in this learning area
この学習エリアでみるこのビデオは
will be written in C# but we'll also
C# で書かれてますが、
provide the Javascript equivalent
同等のJavascript 分はビデオの下の
beneath the video.
表示されています。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)